<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>MATH on Matt&#39;s Tech Blog</title>
    <link>https://mmlind.github.io/tags/math/</link>
    <description>Recent content in MATH on Matt&#39;s Tech Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mmlind.github.io/tags/math/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Using logistic regression to classify images</title>
      <link>https://mmlind.github.io/post/2017-12-26-using_logistic_regression_to_classify_images/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mmlind.github.io/post/2017-12-26-using_logistic_regression_to_classify_images/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this blog post I show how to use logistic regression to classify images. Logistic regression is a statistical method for binary classification, i.e. for analyzing the dependency of a binary outcome on one or more independent variables.
    In a previous blog post I described linear regression. If you’re not familiar with linear regression read that post first.
Let’s briefly recap:
Linear Regression Linear regression is a statistical method for predicting the value of a continuous dependent variable based on one or several explanatory variables.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding linear regression</title>
      <link>https://mmlind.github.io/post/2017-03-05-understanding_linear_regression/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mmlind.github.io/post/2017-03-05-understanding_linear_regression/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Regression represents one of the cornerstones of machine learning. Comprehending its logic and math provides a solid foundation for learning more advanced machine learning techniques such as neural networks.
    Linear regression is a statistical method for modeling the relationship between variables. It’s used for analyzing dependencies and predicting values.
The underlying idea of linear regression is simple: given a dataset, we want to find the dependency of one of the variables in the dataset on one, some or all of the other variables.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
