<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Machine Learning on Matt&#39;s Tech Blog</title>
    <link>https://mmlind.github.io/tags/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Machine Learning on Matt&#39;s Tech Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>2015–2020 by Matt Lind</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mmlind.github.io/tags/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Using logistic regression to classify images</title>
      <link>https://mmlind.github.io/posts/using_logistic_regression_to_solve_mnist/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mmlind.github.io/posts/using_logistic_regression_to_solve_mnist/</guid>
      <description>In this blog post I show how to use logistic regression to classify images. Logistic regression is a statistical method for binary classification, i.e. for analyzing the dependency of a binary outcome on one or more independent variables.
In a previous blog post I described linear regression. If you&amp;rsquo;re not familiar with linear regression read that post first.
Linear Regression vs Logistic Regression Let&amp;rsquo;s briefly recap:
Linear Regression Linear regression is a statistical method for predicting the value of a continuous dependent variable based on one or several explanatory variables.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding linear regression</title>
      <link>https://mmlind.github.io/posts/linear_regression/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mmlind.github.io/posts/linear_regression/</guid>
      <description>Regression represents one of the cornerstones of machine learning. Comprehending its logic and math provides a solid foundation for learning more advanced machine learning techniques such as neural networks.
Linear regression is a statistical method for modeling the relationship between variables. It&amp;rsquo;s used for analyzing dependencies and predicting values.
The underlying idea of linear regression is simple: given a dataset, we want to find the dependency of one of the variables in the dataset on one, some or all of the other variables.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep neural network for MNIST handwriting recognition</title>
      <link>https://mmlind.github.io/posts/deep_neural_network_for_mnist_handwriting_recognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mmlind.github.io/posts/deep_neural_network_for_mnist_handwriting_recognition/</guid>
      <description>I finally found some time to enhance my neural network to support deep learning. The network now masters a variable number of layers and is capable of running convolutional layers. The architecture is generic, light weight (very small memory footprint) and super fast. :-)
In a previous blog post I wrote about a simple 3-Layer neural network for MNIST handwriting recognition that I built. Its architecture &amp;ndash; a 3-layer structure with exactly 1 hidden layer &amp;ndash; was fix.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple 3-layer neural network for MNIST handwriting recognition</title>
      <link>https://mmlind.github.io/posts/simple_3-layer_neural_network_for_mnist_handwriting_recognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mmlind.github.io/posts/simple_3-layer_neural_network_for_mnist_handwriting_recognition/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve extended my simple 1-Layer neural network to include a hidden layer and use the back propagation algorithm for updating connection weights. The size of the network (number of neurons per layer) is dynamic. It&amp;rsquo;s accuracy in classifying the handwritten digits in the MNIST database improved from 85% to &amp;gt;91%.
In a previous blog post I introduced a simple 1-Layer neural network for MNIST handwriting recognition. It was based on a single layer of perceptrons whose connection weights are adjusted during a supervised learning process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple 1-layer neural network for MNIST handwriting recognition</title>
      <link>https://mmlind.github.io/posts/simple_1-layer_neural_network_for_mnist_handwriting_recognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mmlind.github.io/posts/simple_1-layer_neural_network_for_mnist_handwriting_recognition/</guid>
      <description>In this post I&amp;rsquo;ll explore how to use a very simple 1-layer neural network to recognize the handwritten digits in the MNIST database.
In my previous blog post I gave a brief introduction how neural networks basically work. In this post I want to apply this know-how and write some code to recognize handwritten digits in images.
Image Recognition For the computer an image is just a collection of pixels with different colors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is a neural network?</title>
      <link>https://mmlind.github.io/posts/what_is_a_neural_network/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mmlind.github.io/posts/what_is_a_neural_network/</guid>
      <description>When people talk about artificial intelligence and machine learning, they most often refer to (artificial) neural networks (ANN or NN). Let&amp;rsquo;s explore some machine learning basics, without excessive math, purely from a programmer&amp;rsquo;s perspective.
A neural network is a computation model imaging the brain where individual nodes (neurons) form an organism (a network) to process information. In order to understand what this means and how this is special, let&amp;rsquo;s start by looking at how a computer normally works.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
