<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>MULTIPROCESSING on Matt&#39;s Tech Blog</title>
    <link>https://mmlind.github.io/tags/multiprocessing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in MULTIPROCESSING on Matt&#39;s Tech Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mmlind.github.io/tags/multiprocessing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Reading all of Wikipedia in 6 seconds: how to utilize multiple cores to process very large text files</title>
      <link>https://mmlind.github.io/post/2020-10-16-reading_all_of_wikipedia_in_6_seconds_how_to_utilize_multiple_cores_to_process_very_large_text_files/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mmlind.github.io/post/2020-10-16-reading_all_of_wikipedia_in_6_seconds_how_to_utilize_multiple_cores_to_process_very_large_text_files/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I was about to do some basic natural language processing (NLP) task on a large text file: create a dictionary of unique words and count how many times each word occurs. Easy peasy. This should only take me a minute. So I thought. While coding did not take more than 2 zips of coffee, I needed to wait almost an hour for the task to complete. That was unacceptable. There must be a way to accelerate this process.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to simultaneously write to shared memory with multiple processes</title>
      <link>https://mmlind.github.io/post/2020-10-05-how_to_simultaneously_write_to_shared_memory_with_multiple_processes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mmlind.github.io/post/2020-10-05-how_to_simultaneously_write_to_shared_memory_with_multiple_processes/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Most of our modern day computers have more than one processing unit. They are often referred to as cores. For a developer, effectively using multiple cores simultaneously to speed up program execution by parallel processing comes with challenges. One of them is changing the value of a variable in shared memory.
In this blog post I introduce one of the two most common methods to overcome this problem by synchronizing access to shared memory: fork and semaphores.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
